youngzine.org 2017-06-02

# Privacy Policy | Youngzine

Youngzine respects and protects the privacy of our users. Your child's privacy is extremely important to us and we are committed to providing a safe and secure environment for our young readers. 

**Collection, Use and Disclosure of Information**

At Youngzine, we collect the following personal information from a child or adult when they register \- their email address, a unique password applicable to the site, their screen name, and parent's email address if the child is under 13. Some of our users may join Youngzine through an integrated service such as Google - in this case we only require them to pick a screen name.

The only use we make of personal information from our users is to respond to a request for information, to confirm receipt of an article sent by the child and to send periodic newsletters. We do not otherwise make use of personal information, nor do we provide it to third parties. We request parent's email address to forward them a copy of the newsletter and keep them informed of any articles submitted by their child.

**Parental Consent**

We will seek parental consent before collecting any other personally identifiable information. Parents may always request information on the type of data being collected, view their child’s information, and, if they choose, prohibit us from making further use of their child’s information. We will not provide any personal information to third parties.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small text files that are stored on a user's computer and allow websites to "remember" information about users for login and tracking points. The information in cookies is used for personalizing the experience on the site (winning points, and the standard "Remember me" feature). We do not store any personal information in these cookies, nor do we provide any cookie information to third parties. Users can choose to remove cookies through their browser's Tools menu, or disable "Remember me".

**User Generated Content**

We encourage our young users to contribute comments to articles, rate articles, and participate in polls. All such comments are moderated by our Editorial team before they appear on the site. None of the above information is used for any other purpose other than displaying on the site. We also encourage users to contribute text articles. If suitable, our Editorial Staff edits the content, and publishes the final version on the site. On articles contributed by children that we choose to publish, we ask for the first name and age. No other personal information about the child is published on the website.

**Policy on comments**

Youngzine encourages our young users to comment on articles and all such comments are moderated by our Editorial team before they appear on the site. We reserve the right to publish or decline any comments. We encourage comments that show both points of view as long as the comments are positive and respect other opinions. We will not publish any negative or sensational comments even if they come from children.

**Links to external sites**

When children click on links from Youngzine, we will open these in a separate browser window. We make every effort to link to appropriate outside sites. Unlike Youngzine, however, these outside sites may collect personal information. Parents should exercise the same caution and filters as they do currently. 

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about our privacy policy, please use our Feedback form.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

Due to the changing nature of the internet, this privacy policy may be modified at any time at our discretion. It is your responsibility to refer to this privacy policy periodically. If we make any significant changes, we will inform all our users by email.
